它给了你很大的自由来试验你的代码，
It gives you a lot of freedom to experiment with your code,
其中一个真正有用的功能是显示文件之间的差异。
and one of the features that can really help is showing the differences between files.
让我们回到我们的项目，
Let's go back into our project,
我要去这个自述文档，删掉最后一段。
and I'm going to go to this readme document and delete this last paragraph right here.
然后保存它，然后输入“git diff”，
Then I'll go ahead and save it, and I'll do a "git diff" Now,
这个命令将向您展示这两个文件之间的区别。
this command is going to show you the difference between these two files.
你可以看到我们已经删除了 这就是这里减号的意思
You can see that we have deleted, and that's what this minus means right here.
不仅是段落 还有这里的回车
Not only the paragraph, but also this carriage return that was right here.
现在我们来撤销这个，保存它，清除这个，我们再做一次git diff。
Now let's go ahead and undo this and save it, clear this out, and we'll do a git diff again.
这两者之间没有区别
There's no differences between those two.
如果我们要做更多的改变 我们来添加一个新文件夹
And if we do some more changes, let's go ahead and add a new folder.
我们叫它docs。我要把所有HTML文档移到那个docs文件夹。
We'll call it docs. And I'm going to move all of my HTML documents onto that docs folder.
现在我们来试一下。Git diff现在它向我们展示了所有不同的更改，
Now let's try doing it. Git diff Now it's showing us all the different changes,
但这里的变化涉及到搬迁。
but the changes here involved a move.
如果你还记得上个视频中我们看到的移动意味着删除一个文件，
And if you remember from the last video we saw that moving means that your deleting a file,
然后再添加另一个文件。
and then you're adding another file.
因此 为了看到整个变化 我必须一直向下滚动很长时间
So to see this entire change, I have to scroll all the way down for a long time.
当你看到这里的冒号时，如果你想退出，你可以按Q键。
Whenever you see that colon right there, if you want to exit, you can hit the Q key.
让我们把这些清理掉
Let's go ahead and clear this out.
当您有很多更改时，在终端中使用git diff命令有点困难。
And it's a little bit difficult to use that git diff command in the terminal whenever you have a lot of changes.
为此，Visual Studio Code提供了一个源代码控制编辑器。
So to do that, the Visual Studio Code provides a source control editor.
现在你可以看到发生了什么
Now here you can see what happened.
我们删除了这三个文件 并更新或添加了其他这些文件
We have deleted these three files and updated or added these other files.
记住，重命名或移动东西会导致这些变化，
Remember that renaming or moving things causes these kind of changes,
但是您可以看到，这些更改被记录为删除文件，然后更新一些其他文件。
but you can see that the changes are recorded as a deletion of files and then an updating of some other files.
这个屏幕有很多功能，
There's a lot of functionality that this screen has,
例如，如果我点击这个加号，我可以直接从这个界面进行修改。
e.g., if I click on this plus sign, I can go ahead and stage the changes directly from this interface.
我们可以查看一下git状态，然后添加所有的文件。
And we can take a look at git status and go ahead and add all the files.
让我们把所有的东西都添加到暂存版中，这样就会自动更新它。
let's just go ahead and add everything into staging, and that automatically will update it.
一切都在这里 这很酷
Everything that is right here. That's pretty cool.
让我们继续并提交此更改
Let's go ahead and commit this change.
对吧 您可以看到 在这个源代码控制选项卡中不再有任何更改
Right? You can see that there are no longer any changes in this source control tab.
我们回到编辑器 把这个清除掉
We'll go back into the editor, and let's go ahead and clear this out.
diff是很灵活的。你可以用它来比较所有类型的事物。
Now, diff is pretty flexible. You can use it to compare all types of things.
例如 你可以将一个文件与其在任何一次提交时的状态进行比较
So, e.g. you can compare a file to its state at any one of your other commits.
通过比较历史记录 您可以经常检查日志 看看当日志变得非常长时发生了哪些更改
By comparing history, you'll often check the log to see what the changes were when your logs get really long.
如果我现在执行git日志，
So if I do a git log right now,
你可以看到我得到了滚动的文本，这可能很长。
you can see that I get that scrolling text, and this can be really long.
因此，有一种更好的方法来做git日志，那就是使用online标志。
So there is a better way to do a git log, and that is with the online flag.
这将按顺序提交 并将它们全部显示在一行中
This puts the commits in order and also shows them to you all in a single line.
可以看出它在开头有一些散列，
Can tell that it has a little bit of the hash at the beginning,
加上头指针指向主分支的事实，然后是提交消息。
plus the fact that the head pointer is pointing to the main branch, and then the commit messages.
这是查看你的提交的好方法，
This is a great way to take a look at your commit,
这也是一个很好的方法来查看和比较你现在所做的和其他的提交。
and it's also a great way to take a look and compare what you've done right now with some other commit.
如果我想的话，我可以用git diff输入这些提交，
So if I wanted to, I can do a git diff and type in one of these other commits here,
它会向你展示这两次提交之间的区别。
and it's going to show you the differences between those two commits.
现在，这不是很有用，
Now, this is not as useful,
如果你在分支和检查点之间做很多不同的事情，你应该尝试使用一个扩展。
and there is an extension that you should try using if you are doing a lot of diffing between branches and checkpoints.
它叫做GitLens，你可以从Visual Studio Code市场获得它。
It's called GitLens, and you can get it from the Visual Studio Code marketplace.